henrico.us 2019-12-14

# Privacy Policy - Henrico County, Virginia

Henrico County respects your privacy and is committed to protecting your personal information while using our web site and mobile application.

## Information Collected

When the Henrico County website or mobile application is visited, information like the following is collected automatically:

  * The pages visited
  * Terms searched
  * The date and time visited
  * Arrival path to henrico.us site (either through links on other sites or search terms)
  * ISP and general geographical location
  * General technical information on the device used to access the site (web browser, operating system, and if a desktop or mobile device)
  * Crash logs (on mobile application, if enabled by the user)
  * Events taken on the site like clicking a link, downloading a file, or clicking a phone number

This data is collected in aggregate form (i.e., grouped together with everyone else’s, not by individual user). We use this data to analyze trends and data on how our site is used. This includes topics such as how many people visit the site, how people got to the site, and how people are using the website and mobile application. We are able to provide a better service to our users by researching this data.

We use Google Analytics for analytics on henrico.us. We use Microsoft App Center for analytics on the mobile application. We use Microsoft Azure and Google Firebase for notifications on the mobile app. Please visit [Google’s Privacy Policy](https://policies.google.com/privacy) and [Microsoft Enterprise and Developer Products Privacy Policy](https://privacy.microsoft.com/en-US/privacystatement#mainenterprisedeveloperproductsmodule) for more information on their privacy policies.

## Disclosure of Information

Our site offers several online services, where users can submit forms to various departments in the County to interact with various services or programs that the County offers. For example, suppose the [Restaurant Complaint Form](http://henrico.us/services/restaurant-complaint-form/) is used to file a complaint about a restaurant in Henrico County. That page asks for personally identifiable information such as name, address, and phone number. The appropriate agency receives this information, and will only share with other County agencies that might need the information to resolve the issue.

Henrico County does not sell or market such information in any way, to anyone. Henrico County will disclose such information to third parties only when required to do so by law enforcement.

Please be aware that information submitted through this website may be considered a public record subject to release by the County in response to a request made under the [Virginia Freedom of Information Act](http://www.vita.virginia.gov/about/).

GIS and other location-aware apps may use, only with express permission, geographical information to improve the functionality of the application. If using a smartphone, a location warning will ask, “(This app) would like to use your current location,” providing the option to accept or decline. If declined, the current location is not available in that application.

## Cookies

> “A cookie is a small piece of text sent to your browser by a website you visit. It helps the website to remember information about your visit, like your preferred language and other settings. That can make your next visit easier and the site more useful to you. Cookies play an important role. Without them, using the web would be a much more frustrating experience.” – From [Google’s Policies and Principles](https://policies.google.com/technologies/cookies?hl=en).

Cookies are a common part of using the web today, as is privacy. Users have the choice to disable or customize the use of cookies in their browsers. It is up to the user to enable this type of feature. By disabling cookies, certain parts of the web may not work as designed.

A few parts of our websites use cookies, including but not limited to:

  * Analytic tracking on [henrico.us](http://henrico.us/)

Google Analytics will create cookies on behalf of our domain to assist with analytical tracking. Please see Google Analytics document entitled ‘[Safeguarding your data](http://www.google.com/analytics/learn/privacy.html)‘ for more information about cookie usage.

Software on our site or affiliated sites that we use for several functions may also leave cookies for the functionality of the site.

## Henrico Applications

Separate Henrico County web applications display information that is public. Examples include, but are not limited to, Police Public Crime Data, Active Police Calls, Building Inspection information, Subdivision Plats, Traffic, and Real Estate data.

## Links to Third-Party Websites

Some Henrico County web and mobile application pages have links to web sites outside of the County’s web site (henrico.us). Links to other websites are included due to relevance or interest, and do not constitute endorsement by Henrico County.

If these links are clicked to visit other sites, the privacy policies of those sites go into effect while they are being visited, rather than the County’s policies. Henrico County is not responsible for the content or maintenance of the linked remote pages.

## Searching our site

Our website offers searching of the site, backed by Swiftype, an Elastic company. The software tracks search terms used on the site, but it does not correlate a search term to a user. We use this data to assist users to find information quicker on common search terms. This software adheres to [Swiftype’s Privacy Policy](https://swiftype.com/privacy).

## Accessibility

Henrico County works to implement accessibility standards that ensure access to our websites by persons with disabilities. If you have any suggestions for ways to improve accessibility, please contact us at [webmaster@henrico.us](mailto:webmaster@henrico.us).

## Traffic Monitoring

We monitor our incoming Internet traffic to protect our network against incoming cyber attacks and spam. This process can capture and filter traffic depending on IP addresses.

## SSL

All information to and from the henrico.us web site is encrypted.

## Mobile Application

In addition to the analytics data that is collected as mentioned above, the mobile application also stores user entered search terms when viewed on the device to enhance the user experience and provide a history of search terms used within the application.

The application is set up to allow push notification messages. Push notifications can be stopped at any time by simply adjusting the notification phone settings.

The mobile application has links to the county website, as well as other external sites, for additional information.

## Photo Usage

Photographs on the website and mobile application have been taken by various county employees and photographers and are not used for solicitation or monetary purposes. We use photographs taken at Henrico County locations and events which may or may not include the written permission of persons shown in the photos.

## Social Media Policy

## iFrames

Without prior approval and written permission, frames may not be created around the henrico.us web pages which alter in any way the visual presentation or appearance of this website. 

## Updates

Henrico County reserves the right to change these policies and the corresponding information on this page at any time without prior notice.

## Contact Henrico County

Post Office Box 90775  
Henrico, VA 23273-0775  
(804) 501-4000  
8:00 a.m. – 4:30 p.m. Eastern time

Additional contact information can be found on our website, <https://henrico.us/contact-us>.

_Last updated:  January 16, 2019_
